ORLANDO ANDRÉS SUÁREZ

SYSTEMS AND COMPUTING ENGINEER

ABOUT ME

Systems Engineer with over eight years of experience in both Back-end and Front-end development. I'm known for my quick learning skills and ability to handle different tasks responsibly and efficiently. I'm great at solving problems and working well in teams to achieve our goals. I've picked up a lot of knowledge in development tools and languages through my work and my own exploration. I'm also good at managing customer relationships, helping them understand their needs and providing support when they need it.

HARD SKILLS

- Java
- Pvthon
- · Angular, React, VueJS
- Spring Boot, Spring Core, Data, Security, Web
- Postgres, MySQL, DB2, MongoDB, Oracle, Sybase
- AWS S3, EC2, Beanstalk, DynamoDB, SQS listeners
- Docker
- Jenkins

SOFT SKILLS

- Effective communication abilities
- Dependable and professional demeanor
- · Strong organizational skills
- · Proficient in time management
- Dedicated and committed
- Quick to grasp new concepts
- Intrinsic motivation
- Flexible and adaptable attitude

EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer Unosquare | May 2021 - Present

- Developed REST services for an ecommerce system specializing in pet food products.
- Implement REST services for a risk analyst platform.
- Implemented SQS listeners for a S3 bucket.
- Used PostgreSQL and its fast refresh module to implement materialized views, enhancing query performance and data accessibility.

Backend Engineer Omni Latam | Dec 2020 - May 2021

- Learned Python and Django
- Accomplished 100% coverage for testing events in electronic payroll system.
- Developed Radian App covering Electronic Invoicing Events.

Senior systems analyst - Full stack Dev Asesoftware | Aug 2019 - Dec 2020

- Skilled in implementing web services, including REST and SOAP protocols.
- Experienced in frontend development using Angular and AngularJS frameworks.
- Contributed to projects within the insurance industry, including the development of systems for national driver information management, specifically in Colombia.

Senior systems analyst Asnet LTDA | May 2017 - Jul 2019

- Skilled in backend and frontend development for banking institutions.
- Proficient in analysis, software design, and managing frameworks like Struts,
 Primefaces, and base 24 messaging.
- Experienced in implementing web services.
- Trained new team members.
- Actively involved in projects as transactions managers and banking website development for customer transactions.

Development engineer Middlesoftware - Cobiscorp S.A. Aug 2016 - Apr 2017

 Java Web development with Corporative framework based on angular Js, Soap web services implementation with JAXB, store procedures development in Sybase, front and back implementations.

Programmer Heinsohn Business Technology Mar 2016- Aug 2016

- Java Web development with JSF,
 Angular, Seam, JEE, JBOSS web
 aplication server, persistence with JPA
 and hibernate, UML design, Scrum
 methodology, Oracle Database.
- Learned methodologies in software testing.

EDUCATION

Systems and Computing Engineer

National University of Colombia - Bogotá (2010-2016)

ADDITIONAL COURSES

- CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to. CISCO. (2014)
- **CCNA R&S:** Routing and Switching Essentials. CISCO. (2014)

LANGUAGUES

Spanish: Native

English: Proficient

CONTACT

oasuarezm@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andres-suárez/

(+57) 317-341 7691